CHRIS REINER

200 W Hill Rd., Marlborough, MA 01752 ■ 413-244-9177 ■ cjreiner@gmail.com

Analytics professional with experience in digital marketing, product management, pricing and financial planning. Extensive expertise in data analysis, reporting, and data visualization tools, as well as marketing technology in the Google and Salesforce ecosystems.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

BOSTON SCIENTIFIC, Marlborough, MA

2018-Present

Group Manager, Enterprise Marketing Analytics (08/2018-Present)

- Founded the first marketing analytics team at the company, growing the team from 1.5 to 11 people.
- Introduced Agile Scrum methodology to prioritize work, set stakeholder expectations and improve collaboration among the analytics team.
- Implemented Google Analytics 360, designed, coded and implemented a single data layer taxonomy across 80+ websites.
- Oversaw the creation of over 100 campaign dashboards, helping drive a data focused marketing mindset.

PLYMOUTH ROCK ASSURANCE, Boston, MA

2010-2018

Director of Marketing Analytics (09/2014-08/2018)

- Developed and launched the marketing plan for Road Rewards, a safe driving app and rewards program.
- Expanded the use of Salesforce to improve marketing operations, including the automation of manual compensation, and implementing DocuSign.
- Managed the development of direct mail models. Tested various approaches, including Logistic Regression, Random Forests, and Gradient Boosted models.
- Led analysis on direct sales programs for both online and direct mail campaigns. Developed a financial roadmap to reach target cost per sale requirements.

Managing Director (03/2013 - 8/2014)

Product Manager (10/2011 – 03/2013)

- Led the company's re-entry into the Connecticut market. Developed a financial plan and marketing strategy. Repriced the product using generalized linear models and competitive data. Efforts resulted in 75% growth in the first year.
- Identified gaps in Homeowners underwriting. Initiated projects to improve underwriting guidelines and processes resulting in reduced incidence of large losses.
- Monitored profit and competitive results and identified an opportunity to implement unplanned rate revisions to help ensure my markets remained on target to the annual plan.

Marketing Analytics Manager (2/2010 – 10/2011)

- Founded an analytics team focused on serving a data-starved marketing organization.
- Implemented Salesforce.com to improve management oversight of marketing efforts.
- Performed a gap analysis of data needs and identified a suite of for sales, retention, loss ratio, and mix management. Oversaw the development of the report suite.

HANOVER INSURANCE GROUP, Worcester, MA

2006-2010

State Management Analyst (6/2008 – 2/2010)

- Built financial models and presented to senior management on a \$10m opportunity.
- Uncovered gaps in customer account rounding metrics. Developed a new algorithm to accurately identify customer accounts which identified gaps in profitability.
- Improved the accuracy of cross-sell lead reports allowing the relaunch of prior crosssell programs which had been stopped due to inaccurate data.

Regional Finance Director - Massachusetts (9/2006 – 6/2008)

- Implemented a new monthly reporting package and review process which reduced and focused the reporting to actionable information and improved attendance to our monthly round table review meetings.
- Created multiple financial models and presentations recommending the company's course of action under Massachusetts auto insurance reform.

MASSMUTUAL FINANCIAL GROUP, Springfield, MA

2001-2006

Director, Sales Reporting (2006)

- Managed a sales reporting team with an audience of over one-hundred sales offices.
- Received the company's annual Service Star award for building an exceptional service reputation.

Finance Consultant (2003 – 2005)

- Performed analysis on sales and expense results within a captive agency distribution system.
- Analyzed and recommended proposals to improve compensation programs.

Data Management Analyst (2001 – 2002)

• Specialized in agent compensation and provided customer service to agency owners and sales managers.

EDUCATION

B.S. Information Technology, 2022 Expected Graduation, University of Massachusetts, Lowell, MA Master of Business Administration, 2005, University of Massachusetts, Amherst, MA B.A. Economics, Magna Cum Laude, 2001, Framingham State College, Framingham, MA

TECHNICAL SKILLS

SQL, Excel, Tableau, Salesforce, BigQuery, Google Analytics, Google Tag Manager, Javascript, HTML/CSS, C, R, Machine Learning, Lead Scoring, Attribution Modeling, Media Mix Modeling

CERTIFICATIONS

Salesforce Certified Administrator, earned 9/2015

Salesforce Certified Advanced Administrator, earned 3/2016

Salesforce Certified Platform App Builder, earned 3/2016

Salesforce Certified Platform Developer I, earned 12/2016

Salesforce Certified Service Cloud Consultant, earned 8/2017

Salesforce Marketing Cloud Email Specialist, earned 4/2018

Tableau Desktop 10 Qualified Associate, earned 11/2016